# Jonathan Baruc

I am deeply passionate about the intersection of systems engineering and user delight. I'm a lifelong design thinker who's dedicated the last 10 years of my career to producing world-class UI/UX experiences, building award-winning products from discovery, through development, release, and refinement.



#### Experience



#### **UX/UI Consultant**

Praction New York, NY, July 2023 - January 2024

Overhauled the entire software UX in under 2 months and collaborated with product to develop long-term research and design strategy, leading to an increase in client retention and engagement on the platform

Championed and implemented a design system to improve user experience for Praction's AI-powered revenue growth platform.



#### **Senior Product Designer**

Native Instruments Berlin, Germany, November 2014 - January 2022

Regularly owned projects from Discovery through Development and Release.

Led the end-to-end design, specification (Figma), and launch of Native Access app, used by 1.5 million users worldwide.

Created sketches, mock ups, wireframes, prototypes on a weekly basis for B2B and consumer products utilizing Figma, Sketch Adobe Suite, Storybook, and Miro.

Design the screens for and ship the world's best-selling MIDI keyboard, pioneering accessibility, leading to upwards of \$50 million in sales.

# Unify brand through micro-behaviors, experience and products

Collaborated with the executive team to translate corporate missions and goals into product strategy and products in company incubator using design thinking, on-site user research, rapid prototyping executive presentations.

Helped build, optimize and document the Lumen Design System and component library, leading to a 50% reduction in product development time and an increase in overall team productivity.

Reformed design strategy to drive a 3x increase in monthly active users, accountable for 7.5% of attributed revenue.

Ideated, prototyped, and produced the universal browser UI; implemented user centric design principles, generating \$10 million in sales first quarter of release.

**Explore my work at Native Instruments here** 

# Introduce new methodology, practice and technology

Founded and executed an interactive e-learning program for the major product line.

Owned research and prototyping on the MK3 hardware keyboard experience.

Introduced tools such as Appzi, usertesting.com, Upvoty and Grain.co, to increase the rate of gathering user feedback 10x.

Migrated entire Design System and working files from Sketch to Figma.

Conducted qualitative and quantitave user research, user testing, and A/B testing utilizing Centercode, Mixpanel, Metabase, Quantilope, Google Analytics to enrich company user research data lake.

Evangalized the importance of user experience and user centric design throughout the Product teams.



## Head of Design & Co-founder

Building Conversation Boston, MA, September 2012 -October 2014

Led user research, interface design and feature discovery on an augmented reality engine for architects and real estate developers.

Drove collaboration between product ops and engineering to ship beautiful, easy-to-use features.



# Head of Design & Business Development

Together Festival Cambridge, MA, January 2011 - August 2012

Secured over \$200K in sponsorship and in-kind deals through targeted outreach and negotiation strategies.

Developed and curated the daytime programming, aligning brand awareness with educational lectures, workshops, and demos.

Orchestrated the development of a cutting-edge design system that flawlessly integrated over 60 top brands, resulting in 100% brand recognition.

### Education

### **Dual BFA, Multimedia & Graphic Design**

Northeastern University Boston, Massachusetts, September 2008 - May 2012

### **Tools**

Figma

Sketch **Abstract** 

Adobe Creative Suite

Storybook

Miro

Mixpanel Metabase

**JIRA** 

Zeplin

Centercode

Upvoty

Appzi Maze Al

Usertesting.com

Quantilope

Google Analytics

Git

Html / CSS / Javascript

### Skills

Discovery

Ideation **Design Systems** 

**Design Strategy** 

Design Thinking

**Design Sprints Design Specifications** 

**UX Research** 

**User Personas User Flow Mapping User Testing** 

Usability & Accessibility

Prototyping Wireframing

**User Flows** 

**Digital Solutions B2B Enterprise Software** 

Information Architecture

### Contact

Beta Community Development Workshop Facilitation

**Executive Presentations** 

Visual Narratives

Quantitative Research

**Competitor Analysis Data Analytics Customer Journey Mapping Customer Insights** 

Desktop Design Mobile Design

Participatory Design Cadence & Iterative Design Agile Environment

Dually based in Bedford Hills NY Philadelphia, PA Open to relocation

jdbaruc@gmail.com (347) 963 6657